天哪 这太糟糕了
God, that is really bad.
我们能把这堆破玩意弄走吗
Can't we get this shit out of here?
得等到停工结束
Not until the shutdown is over.
垃圾回收暂停服务了...
The garbage collection is suspended...
等等 怎么了?
Wait, what?
我是不是听到副总统尖叫了?
Did I hear the VP scream?
不 那是我 而且那是在大喊
No, that was me. And it was a shout.
垃圾堆里有只老鼠
There was a rat on the garbage,
所以我大喊把它吓走
so I shouted to scare it off.
那是男人的声音?  当然 因为我是个男人
- That was a man's voice? - Yeah, 'cause I'm a man.
我有副男人的嗓子
I have a man's voice.
哦 没错 走开
Yeah, that's right. Walk away.
走开点
Walk away.
我向上帝发誓 那超大的
I swear to God, it was massive.
就像匹小马  吱吱 吱吱
- It was like a pony. - Squeak, squeak.
神啊 停! 这一点都不酷
God! Stop! That's not cool.
好吧 伙计们 我就开门见山了
Okay, guys, I'm not gonna drag this out.
我们正处于停工阶段
We're in shutdown mode.
我得留下骨干员工
I've got to have a skeleton staff.
那么Keith留下来 对吗  什么?
- So Keith stays, right? - What?
Keith 他瘦的只剩骨干了
Keith. He's skinny like a skeleton.
女士 求你 我负担不起停职
Ma'am, please. I can't afford to be furloughed.
不 不是你 但是 Dan 是你  女士
- No, you're not. But, Dan, you are. - Ma'am.
哦 你知道的 你们两个做类似的工作
Yeah, you know, you two do similar jobs.
从经济意义上来说你走更合适 Dan
It just makes economic sense for you to go, Dan.
那是说他挣的比我多?
Does that mean he makes more money than I do?
不管怎么说 这不会太久
Anyway, the deal is it's not going to be long
因为今天我会和议长会晤
because I've got a meeting with the Speaker today.
对吧?  今天 是的
- Is that correct? - Today, yes.
所以我会停止这次停工
So I'm gonna shut down the shutdown.
看起来会在你我之间做出选择
It looks like it's between you and me.
没有我 这办公室会崩溃
Without me, this office will implode.
Gary 情报局称你为少女秀兰·邓波儿（著名童星）
Gary, the Secret Service is calling you Girly Shirley Temple.
所以你只需要切...  Sue
so You need to Just cut... - Sue.
哈?  你也要回家
- Yeah? - You're going home.
Oh!
哦 我很抱歉  没事
- Yeah, I'm sorry. - Fine.
我需要独处一下
I need a moment.
哦 伙计 那真残酷
Oh, man, that's tough.
哦 上帝啊 我为她感到难过
Oh, my God. I feel so bad for her.
嘿 她得离开  可怜的Sue
- Come on, she had to go. - Poor Sue.
可怜的Sue  我猜我得出去了
- Poor Sue. - I guess I'll be heading out.
好吧 我需要提醒你 你不能和这里的任何人有工作上的联系
Okay. I need to remind you you cannot make work-related contact with anyone
同时你也被法律禁止
from this administration and you're forbidden by law
进入西翼或者行政楼
from entering the West Wing or EEOB.
事实上 你不需要提醒我那个
Actually, you did not need to remind me of that.
我知道 但我就是想  拜
- I know, but I wanted to. - Laters.
喔 他情绪处理得很好
Wow, he's taking that well.
他就是个Spock（《星际迷航》中的半外星人） 他不会泄露他的情绪
He's like Spock. He doesn't show his emotions.
从不?  从不
Ever? - Ever.
从不?
Ever?
不 那时也不会  你在开玩笑
- No, not even then. - You're kidding me.
我有次看到他因为一个保安
I saw him laugh once really hard
从电动车上摔下来而放声大笑
when the security guy fell off his Segway.
大笑是感情吗?
Is laughter an emotion?
全天spa一条龙
Full day spa package.
不 我认为你会发现这是可行的
No, I think you'll find it is possible.
Sue Wilson.
宝贵的客户 必要时气势会很足
Valued and, if need be, aggressive client.
你能帮我跟他约个午餐么? 棒极了
Can you set up a lunch with him? Great.
不 不 不 只是在人生的商店中
No, no, no. Just browsing the store of life.
探索一下可能性
Section marked what if.
不 不 让我交际...
No, no, network the bejesus...
让我交际到内伤吧
Network the bejesus out of me.
我要人们看我的脸看到恶心为止
I want people to be sick of the sight of my face.
真好笑 Carl
Very funny, Carl.
Gary 我不知道这个怎么弄
Gary, I don't know how to do that.
哦 女士 哦 哦 哦 抱歉
Oh, ma'am. Oh, oh, oh. Sorry.
Andrew向两个党派都捐了款这事被博客到处转载
Andrew donating to both parties is all over the blogs.
该死的到底是谁一直在搅浑水?  Roger Furlong
Who the hell keeps stirring the shit pot? - Roger Furlong.
也想到那个了 太明显了 Furlong
Thought that, too. So obvious, Furlong.
喔 这就像肛瘘
Wow, it's like anal leakage.
捐款 那本讨厌的关于我和Andrew在做戏的书
The donations, the shitty book about me and Andrew
有些假的联系
having some sort of fake relationship,
土地交易 呃 好多年前的那个
the land deal from, like, ages ago.
找个人把Roger Furlong那颗没有下巴的头给我提来
Somebody bring me the chinless head of Roger Furlong.
哦 在致谢中作者说...
Well, in the acknowledgments, the author says...
你为什么会有一本那个?
Why do you have a copy of that?
这样我可以向人们反驳 这是我的驳斥用书
So I can refute it to people. It's my refuting copy.
扔掉 抵制它
Get rid of it. Refuse it.
好吧 瞧 如果VP确有一扇窗(双关 空余时间)
Okay, look, if the VP did have a window,
那会是扇很高的窗子 而她会把你从那推下去
it'd be a high one and she'd push you out of it.
哦 那真不错  我在模仿Sue
- Ooh, that's very good. - I'm doing my impression of Sue.
哦 那真不错  什么?
- Yeah, that's very good. - What?
你怀孕了?  哦 天哪 我很抱歉 我不是故意的
You're pregnant? Oh, my God, I'm so sorry. I did not mean that.
听着 如果你下周打来 我大概能把你安排进去 如何?
Listen, if you call next week, I can probably fit you in, okay?
恭喜
Congratulations.
哦 你们好 政府官员们
Well, 'ello, governors.
腌我大鳗鱼 挠我小肚腩 (仿自诗句 疼我宠我溺爱我)
Pickle me eels and tickle me belly
因为我要休假去伦敦城潇洒
'cause I am off to merry London Town
来一次真正他妈的巡游 呃?
for a right fuckabout, eh?
不过对吧? 哼?
Innit, though? Huh?
你要去伦敦的G8会议?
Are you going to the G8 conference in London?
是的 没错 Gary 感谢询问
Yes, I am, Gary. Thank you for asking.
是的 我会去
Yes, I am.
毫不夸张地说 那是个女人们会整天醉酒的城市
It is a city where women are literally drunk all day.
而我就会去填补她们的空白 我的朋友
And I am going to mind their gaps, my friend.
但是我需要更新我的护照 所以能让我副总统谈谈吗
But I need my passport renewed, so can I speak to the veep?
你为什么要找她?
Why do you need her for that?
哦  吞精上脑亲  政府现在停工了
Well, cum-for-brains, the government is shut down,
因此所有的护照办理处都关门了
so all the passport offices are closed.
所以我需要Selina帮我疏通关系
So I need Selina to pull some strings for me.
所以帮我叫下Sue
So get Sue.
Sue在哪 Sue在哪
Where's Sue? Where's Sue?
谁是那个新的Sue?  我
Who's the new Sue? Me.
你要预约吗 Ryan先生?
Would you like an appointment, Mr. Ryan?
啊 是的 新的Sue 我想预约
Uh, yes, new Sue, I would like to make an appointment.
想得美  哈哈
- Suck it. - Ha ha!
瞧瞧你身边
Look around you.
人们失业 垃圾满街
People out of work. Garbage in the streets.
普通人正在遭受苦难 (Chung州长批评政府停工)
Ordinary folks suffering.
有时候我觉得并不了解我自己的党派
Sometimes I feel I don't know my own party.
瞧 这就是高分辨率的问题
See, this is the problem with high-definition.
你不会想看一只高分辨率的老二
You don't want to see a dick in hi-def.
他们怎么能够允许这次停工发生?
How can they allow this shutdown to happen?
那些在华盛顿拿过
Do Washington's overpaid lawmakers
高工资的立法者不关心普通人吗?
not care about ordinary people?
什么? 我可没有拿过高的工资
What? I'm not overpaid.
我本来就有钱 好吧? 抱歉
I'm independently wealthy. All right? Sorry.
他们得达成协议并且搞定那恶臭
They need to cut a deal and vanquish the stench.
女士 你家的恶臭已经没了
Ma'am, the stench at your home is gone.
多亏了我  什么?
thanks to me. - What?
知道你家外面那堆臭气熏天的垃圾吧?
You know that stinky garbage outside your home?
我 作为Sue 找了家私人公司把它运走了
I, as Sue, had a private company take it away.
什么? 你为什么那么做?
What? Why would you do that?
那不是个好主意 Gary
That was not a good idea, Gary.
这可不是我期待的反应
That wasn't the reaction I was expecting.
嘿 Gary 每个在垃圾城生活的人
Come on, Gary. Everybody in Garbagetown
都得与臭气共存
has to live with the stink except for the...
除了在她香喷喷的宫殿中生活的傲慢公主
uppity princess in her perfumed palace.
那是其他人会说的
Is what other people would say.
我不会那么说 不是我
I'm not saying that. Not me.
等一会 停一下
Wait a minute, hold on now.
那么现在某个
So now some private contractor
没有经过审查的私营承包商
who has not been vetted
可以翻过我所有的垃圾
could go through all of my trash
然后把它放在...
and put it up on the...
网络上?
on the Internet?
抱歉 女士 我不是故意的
I'm sorry, ma'am. I didn't mean to do that.
你得去把那些垃圾袋弄回来
You've got to go and get the garbage bags back.
好的 是 女士 等等 我怎么知道哪些袋子是您的?
Okay. Yes, ma'am. Wait, how am I gonna know which bags are yours?
你想告诉我袋子里有些什么吗?
Do you want to let me know some of the things that are in the bags?
啊哼 我能就...我能和你私下聊一会吗?
Ahem, can I just... can I talk to you privately just for a second?
哦 当然
Yeah, sure.
搞什么...
What the...?
我不知道
- I don't know. - Fuck.
快点  是的 女士
- Be quick. - Yes, ma'am.
所以我和议长 我认为我们将结束这个
So me and the Speaker, I think we're gonna end this.
好吧 总统知道我们得尽快结束停工
Well, POTUS knows we have to get out of shutdown ASAP.
不管从哪个方面 都把我们弄得他妈的一团糟
It's fucking us all every which way.
没错 说到那个...
Yeah. Speaking of which...
女士?
Ma'am?
唔 我有和Andrew见面
Um, I've been seeing Andrew.
见他?
Seeing him?
就像你会因为午餐或打牌去见某些人?
Like you would see someone for lunch or a game of cards?
是的 是的 是的 是的
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我是说 我们一起吃午餐然后...上床
I mean, we've been having lunch and then we've been having sex.
没玩什么牌
And not really cards so much.
只是 你知道的 只是 呃 上床
Just, you know, just, like, sex.
哦 上帝啊  Amy 你能告诉我该怎么做吗?
Oh, God, Amy. Can you tell me what to do?
说真话?  是的
Honestly? - Yeah.
你得把他这样的有毒垃圾倒出去
You dump him overboard like the toxic waste he is.
他会葬送你的事业  别这样 Amy
- He will kill your career. - Come on, Amy.
那实在是很棒
It is just so good.
你只是没概念 那能减压
You just have no idea. And it's stress relief.
你知道 内啡肽 (强效止痛)
You know, endorphins.
好吧 那么你就...你就看事情发展呗
Okay, then you see... see where it goes.
不 我得结束它  没错
- No, I have to end it. - Yeah.
但我做不到
But I can't.
我很高兴我们谈过了 达成了共识
I'm glad we talked. On the same page.
我并不需要实际接触那些垃圾 对吗?
I don't actually have to touch the trash, do I?
不 你得拥抱它们
Yes, you've got to embrace it.
你得帮我把垃圾弄出来 放到你的车上
You've got to help me get the garbage, put it in your car.
我们把它运到官邸 然后我会帮你弄到护照
We'll take it to the residence and I'll help you get a passport.
所以你们就是那些想要回垃圾的人?
So you're the guys who want your trash back?
是的 你是Walker先生吗  没错
Yeah. are You Mr. Walker? - Yes.
嘿 我是 Gary Walsh  很荣幸见到你
- Hey, I'm Gary Walsh. - It's a pleasure.
Jonah Ryan 白宫来的  你好
Jonah Ryan. West Wing. - Hi.
那么 我们的垃圾呢?  你们的垃圾?
- So, our trash? - Your trash?
是的 是的 是的  现在是我的了
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. - It's mine now.
哦  所以 我的好处呢?
- Oh. - So what's my end?
好吧 先生 这是政府要务
Okay, sir, this is a government matter,
所以你最好合作
so it would be best if you cooperated.
你在威胁我吗 发胶头?
Are you threatening me, Pez head?
因为我们有个压缩机
Because we got a compactor that takes shit
能把所有垃圾压成方块
and turns it into cubes.
好吧
Okay.
能让我们单独谈一下吗? 非常感谢
Could you just excuse us for one moment? Thank you so much.
你到底在干什么?
What the hell are you doing?
我们得给他点好处
We have to offer him something.
那你为什么不要求 在回收玻璃的旁边给他吹一管呢?
Why don't you offer to blow him over by the recycled glass?
那会产生些有趣的灯光效果
It would throw up some interesting light effects.
会很浪漫的 不是吗?
That would be romantic, wouldn't it?
你要是去不了伦敦会很可惜
It's a shame you're not going to London.
好吧 行 你知道吗?
Okay, fine. You know what?
我会给他一次游览西翼的机会
I'm gonna offer him a tour of the West Wing.
平民们就爱那一套
Civilians love that shit.
他们对那非常狂热 我叫它湿身西翼
They get so hot for it, I call it the Wet Wing.
好吧 那可不太礼貌  那只是栋建筑 Gary
- Okay, that's disrespectful. - It's a building, Gary.
它没有感觉  它有精神
- It doesn't have feelings. - It has a spirit.
不 它没有 先生 Walsh先生和我愿邀请你
No, it doesn't. Sir, Mr. Walsh and I
来一趟独一无二的私人
would love to offer you a private, exclusive tour
白宫西翼之旅
of the West Wing of the White House.
当然 听起来挺有趣  棒极了
- Sure, that sounds like fun. - Great.
哦 等等 我说了有趣吗?
Oh, wait. Did I say fun?
我的意思大概是你认为我是个傻逼
I meant like you think I'm a dick.
那么你想要什么?
What would you like?
我希望副总统来访问一下
I would like a visit from the vice president.
哦  我希望她能到这里来看看
- Oh. - I'd like to have her take a tour.
我想那会对我的生意很有帮助
I think it'd be good for business.
副总统大力赞赏垃圾压缩
Vice president applauds shit compaction.
好吧 我们能做到 是的
Okay, we can do that. Yeah.
天哪 我都快忘记
Boy, I had forgotten
这个办公室以前有多漂亮了 Jim
how nice this office was, Jim.
它现在很漂亮 不是吗?
It is nice, isn't it?
这些椅子就值一大笔钱
These chairs are worth a fortune.
是吗?  尽管它们极其不舒适
- Are they? - Uncomfortable as hell, though.
是的 是的  对吧?
- Yeah. Yeah. - Right?
好吧 以前的人们大部分时候都过得不怎么舒适
Well, people in the old days lived in discomfort most of the time.
哦 这倒是真的  他们的衣服都把人给织进去了
- Oh, well, that's true. - They were laced into their clothing.
极冷或极热
Freezing cold or hot as hell.
硬梆梆的椅子 还散发着怪味  艰难的时代 艰难的时代
Hard chairs And They All stank. - Tough times. Tough times.
是的 我只是在说70年代  好吧
- Yeah, and I'm just talking about the 1970s. - Okay.
不是的 我说的是18世纪
I'm not. I was thinking of the 18th century.
假发 还有别的  好吧
- The wigs, so on. - All right.
那...我想我们几乎要达成预算协议了
So I think we're pretty close on a budget deal here.
我想我们只需要你让一小步
I think we just need you to move a scooch more.
哦 我不会动  你不动?
- Oh, I'm not moving. - You're not moving?
不会向你让步 女士 你已经被晾起来了
Not with you, ma'am. You have been hung out to dry.
我刚接到《政客》杂志的电话
I just got a call from Politico.
他们刚采访了总统 打电话来是看我的回应
They just did an interview with the president and they called for my reaction.
刚刚? 你在说什么?
Just now? What are you talking about?
你不知道? 你没有 好吧  我没看到...
- Do you not know? You haven't. All right. - I have not seen...
我会不带入个人感情来读总统的话
I will read the president's words without inflection.
滑动解锁
Slide to unlock.
Selina Meyer是个活跃的管理者和不错的副总统
Selina Meyer is a feisty operator and a fine VP.
她尽了最大的努力来避免此次停工
She tried her best to prevent this shutdown,
没日没夜地工作 但这是个艰难的决定
working long hours, but it was a tough call.
潜台词是 女士... 你失败了
Subtext, ma'am... you failed.
而且此次政府停工被归咎到了你头上
And you are being blamed personally for this government shutdown.
好吧 首先 我没听出那个潜台词
Okay, first of all, I did not hear that subtext.
我听到了正文 而我听到的正文是
I hear text, and the text that I hear
活跃而成功的副总统
is a feisty and successful VP.
哦 我不认为他说了成功
Oh, I don't think he said successful.
哦 我知道他说了成功
Oh, I know he said successful.
哦 那不在这些话里
Well, that wasn't in those words.
绝对有 你刚刚念给我听的就是
That's what you just read to me.
抱歉  你随意 随意 你再回去读
- I'm sorry. - Feel free. Yeah, read it back.
Selina Meyer是个活跃的管理者和不错的副总统
Selina Meyer is a feisty operator and a fine VP.
没有成功的  不错的和成功的是同义词
No successful. - Fine And successful are synonyms.
你是在强词夺理  我没有强词夺理
- You're grasping at straws. - I'm not grasping for straws.
这个
What with this
还有所有关于你前夫的报道
and with all those stories about your ex-husband,
大量的负面消息
there's a lot of poison coming
都来自某一个敌对的国会议员
from certain enemy congressmen.
Roger Furlong?
你说是就是吧 对我来说都一样
If you say so. It's all beans to me.
副总统女士 你被挤出了预算协议
Madam Vice President, you have been squeezed out of the budget deal.
这很艰难 但我不在乎
It's tough, but I don't care.
现在你知道我们为什么要有这些硬邦邦的椅子了
Now you see why we have the hard chairs.
几乎不值得你坐下来
Hardly worth you sitting down.
你知道 Jim
You know, Jim,
你比我老很多
you're a lot older than me.
如果你在未来六年内死掉
If you die within the next six years,
我就会参加你的葬礼
I will be attending your funeral
然后在总统派我替他去的时候给你做悼词
and giving a eulogy when POTUS sends me there in his stead.
那里面会充斥着潜台词
And it is gonna be full of subtext.
塞满了潜台词
Chock-full of subtext.
好吧 我期待着 哦 等等 我那时已经死了
Well, I look forward to that. Oh, wait, I'll be dead.
说实在的 Sidney 我将暂时停职
Honestly, Sidney, I'm looking at being furloughed
看作一次机会  哦 没错
- as an opportunity. - Oh, yeah.
出去走走 四处活动 会见人物
Get out there, touch some bases, face some faces.
那么你是说你的事业正停滞不前
So what you're saying is your career has stalled.
所以现在你个懒逼
So now you and your slack pussy
想做石油说客挣大钱 对吗?
want to make big bucks as an oil lobbyist, right?
欢迎 先生们  你好
- Welcome, gentlemen. - Hello.
今天的特价是墨鱼...
Today's specials are the cuttlefish...
让我打断你一下 甜心
Let me stop you right there, sweetheart.
你会结账 对吧?  是的 我请
- You're gonna pick up the tab, right? - Yes, that's on me.
很好 我要最贵的前菜
Great. I'm gonna have the most expensive starter,
最贵的主菜 还有一瓶200美元的香槟
the most expensive entrance, and a $200 bottle of champagne.
是的 先生  你知道 我想我会来点清淡的
- Yes, sir. - You know, I think I'm gonna keep it light.
我要鸡肉沙拉和健怡可乐
I'm gonna go chicken salad and a Diet Coke.
胡说  给他来一份和我一样的
Nonsense. Give him exactly what I'm having.
我们会分享那瓶香槟
And we will split the champagne.
这是我们第一次约会
It's our first date.
(我的丈夫就离守林人小站15码远的地方被杀害)
My husband was killed 15 yards from a ranger's station.
这是最混乱的故事
This is the most fucked-up story.
我是说 被熊弄死了?
I mean, killed by a bear?
(因为停工 没有任何公园守林人值班)
No park rangers on site due to the shutdown.
而且还是只黑熊 这就是奇怪的地方 (黑熊体型较棕熊小 攻击性弱)
And a black bear. That's the weird part.
他们甚少袭击人类 这很奇怪
They rarely attack people. That's weird.
没错 那是我... 他肯定刺激了它
Right. That's what I was... then he must have goaded him.
他肯定拿棍子打了它或者做了些蠢事
He must have hit him with a stick or done something stupid.
嘲弄它或者强迫那只熊跳舞
Taunting him or forcing the bear to dance.
熊不喜欢跳舞  你要来跳个舞吗?
- Bears don't like to dance. - Would you dance, please?
在娱乐行业中没有快乐的熊  或者他试图干那只熊
- There's not a happy bear in show business. - Or he tried to fuck the bear.
他试图干...  就像Grizzly Adams (小说人物 驯熊人)
He tried to fuck... - Like Grizzly Adams.
哦 呀  自娱自乐?
- Oh, jeez. - Enjoying yourselves?
没错  你们在嘲笑
- We were. - Are you laughing
那个年轻男人残酷的死亡?
at the violent death of a young man?
没错 可以那么说  我以为你被暂时停职了 Kent
- Yeah, pretty much. - I thought you were on furlough, Kent.
我的降噪耳机忘在这了
Forgot my noise-cancelling headphones.
猜我刚刚听到了什么
Guess what I just heard.
我不在这 所以 我的耳朵也不在这
I'm not here. Ergo, my ears aren't here either.
好吧 总统的采访中有段引言
Okay. POTUS's quote
在马上要出版的《政客》里
in his soon-to-be-released Politico interview
他将政府停工归咎于我
in which he blames me for the government shutdown.
什么?  没错 什么?
What? - Exactly. What?
那很含蓄  含蓄?
- It was implicit. - Implicit?
含蓄得像在我屁股上贴个踢我贴纸
Implicit like a kick me sticker
那种会含蓄?
on my keister would be implicit?
副总统女士 恕我直言
Madam Vice President, greatest respect,
但一直以来副总统的工作就是
but it has been the job of the VP over the ages
为拯救总统而贡献出屁股
to take it in the ass to save the president.
没错  让我来告诉你
Yeah, let me tell you something.
这个屁股已经停止营业了
This ass is closed for business.
这个屁股正紧闭 我不想当诱饵
This ass is in clench-down. I don't want to be a decoy.
让总统把屁股贡献出来吧 他会喜欢的
Let the president take it in the ass. He might like it.
这些有权力的男人和女人们
These powerful men and women,
他们无法在任何事情上达成共识
they couldn't agree on anything.
你在玩我
You've got to be kidding me.
现在我因为某个蠢货
Now I'm to blame because some goober
被熊啃干净了而遭受指责?
got all eaten up by a bear?
你得把你的媒体人弄来搞定这个 懂吗?
You've got to get your press guys on this, okay?
是的 女士  女士 是在明尼苏达州 好吗?
- Yes, ma'am. - Ma'am, this is in Minnesota, right?
Chung州长会揪住这件事不放
So Governor Chung is gonna be all over this
就像盯住蠢货的熊  当然 没错
- like a bear on an idiot. - Of course. That's right.
至少 采取什么行动
At the very least, let's get in front of something
并且联系上这个寡妇
and get in touch with this widow.
是的 你听到了吗 Mike  呃 呃
- Yeah. Did you hear that, Mike? - Uh-uh.
熊寡妇 跟那个熊寡妇联络
The bear widow. Get in touch with the bear widow.
还有联络那些媒体人?
As well as get in touch with the press guys?
是的 还有那些媒体人
Yeah, as well as get in touch with the press guys.
两件事 打电话给《吉尼斯世界纪录》
Two things. Call the Guinness Book of World Records.
哦 不 不 别 别 因为那会是三件事
Oh, no, no, don't, don't, because that would be three things.
那么你真不打算吃那个龙虾?
So you're really not gonna eat that lobster?
哦 不 我讨厌龙虾
Oh, no, I hate lobster.
你知道的Dan 我们可以用你
You know, Dan, we could use you.
你觉得去内布拉斯加州
How do you feel about swindling
忽悠一群当地二逼们怎么样?
a bunch of sister fuckers out of their land in Nebraska?
我们想装 一条穿过他们地盘的输油管道
We're trying to skirt a pipeline through their backyard
而他们因为某些原因不同意
and they're not a fan for some reason.
你想摆脱一些农场主 嗯?
You want to get rid of some farm folk, huh?
就把我当成你的整装黑风暴吧 我的朋友 (造成30年代美国农业巨大损失的公害事件)
Consider me your well-groomed dust bowl, my friend.
嘿 哦 天哪 你让它抽了一下
Hey, ooh! Boy, you made it twitch.
不过如果你真想让我的老二跳起舞来的话
But if you really want to make my dick dance,
你为什么不告诉我副总统办公室里发生了什么?
why don't you tell me what's going on in the VP's office?
好吧 你知道的 我不能说得太仔细
Well, you know, I can't really be too specific.
当然 当然 不 我们可以...
Sure, sure. No, we can...
我们为什么不用一些代码呢?
why don't we come up with some kind of code?
这里 副总统是龙虾
Here, the VP will be the lobster.
Amy 绿色蔬菜 我们叫Mike胡萝卜
Amy, greens. We'll call Mike carrots.
Dan 你可以是虾
Dan, you can be shrimp.
你看到我做了什么吗 Dan? 我把你变成了虾
Do you see what I did there, Dan? I made you shrimp.
天 我真希望我点了一盘无用的混蛋
Boy, I just wish I ordered a plate of useless assholes.
但你手里有什么兵就只能用什么兵了  对吗? (前国防部长Rumsfeld名言)
But you go to war with the army you have, right?
好吧 我想这只龙虾
Okay, I think the lobster
和她的前夫又走到一起了
is getting back together with her ex-husband.
绿色蔬菜几乎没法控制局面
The greens are only barely keeping it together.
Mike... 胡萝卜债务缠身
Mike... the carrots are drowning in debt.
而这只小虾想听听更多关于内布拉斯加交易的事情
And this little shrimp wants to hear more about this Nebraska deal.
想去大玉米带对吧? (美国中部的大农业带)
Want to go to the corn belt, do you?
我想出击 我想为你一击必杀
I want to hit it. I want to hit it hard for you.
哦 敲敲你的红宝石鞋跟然后赶紧
Well, tap your ruby slippers together
他妈醒醒吧 没有工作 Dorothy  (见《绿野仙踪》)
and wake the fuck up. There is no job, Dorothy.
但我很惊讶你可以出卖
But I'm very impressed that you would turn on
你在副总统办公室的所有伙伴
all of your compadres there in the vice president's office.
那么你为什么不带着你的 甜蜜惊悚小舞蹈去找Danny Chung呢?
So why don't you take your little vanilla Thriller dance over to Danny Chung?
他是目前肮脏政坛里炙手可热的无耻新星
He's the shiny turd rising to the top of the bowl right now.
你就喜欢无耻之徒 不是吗 Dan?
You like turds, don't you, Dan?
是的 不 不 不 不
Yeah. No, no, no, no.
那不是我真正的意思 你误解了 说实在的
That's really not what I meant. You misunderstood, honestly.
当我说失误 我是说那不是你丈夫的失误
When I said fault, I meant that it wasn't your husband's fault
因为熊天生就会饿
because bears are naturally hungry.
那样说你能接受吗
Does that make sense?
喂? 喂?
Hello? Hello?
哦 那是Doolittle夫人吗
Oh, was that Mrs. Doolittle?
是的  然后?
Yeah. - And?
非常情绪化  哦 当然
- Very emotional. - Well, of course.
没错
Yeah.
什么?   哦 苍天啊
What? Oh, Jesus.
好吧 Amy 我们会派Dan
All right, Amy, we're gonna have to get Dan
去明尼苏达 做些寡妇的工作
to go to Minnesota, do some widow work.
Dan在停职中  是 我他妈知道他在停职
- Dan's on furlough. - Yeah, I know he's fucking furloughed
因为是我他妈给他停的职
because I'm the fucker who furloughed him.
顺便问 Gary呢?
And by the way, where is Gary?
还在处理垃圾
He's still getting the garbage.
哦 好吧 如果他不能尽快回来
Well, okay, if he's not back soon,
我们要终止使Sue停职
we're gonna have to unenfurlough Sue.
Unenfur...
终止使...  我们得把Sue召回来 好吧
- - we'll have to get Sue back. Okay.
没错 还有我要见Furlong
Yeah. And I want to meet with Furlong.
想都别想 我不会进去的
It's not happening. I'm not getting in there.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
哦 上帝啊
Oh, God!
哦 拜托 拜托 你觉得这很糟?
Oh, please. Please. You think this is bad?
等你到了伦敦 所有东西闻起来都有股尿骚味
Wait till you get to London. Everything smells like urine.
连食物也是
Even the food.
好吧 找到了
Okay, found it.
你怎么知道这是她的?  闭嘴 我找到了
- How do you know it's hers? - Shut up. I found it.
哦 上帝啊 这披萨真不错
Oh, my God, that pizza was good.
你知道的 我不怎么吃披萨 Roger
You know, I don't eat pizza very much, Roger.
但是当我吃的时候 那让我太他妈的高兴了
But when I do, it just makes me so fucking happy.
为此感谢中国人吧  什么?
Thank the Chinese for that. - What?
中国人发明了披萨 (有此一说)  不 他们没有
- The Chinese invented pizza. - No, they didn't.
是的 是他们  听着 Roger
- Yeah, they did. - Listen, Roger,
来谈谈现在到处传播的
let's talk about all these stories going around
所有关于Andrew的土地交易和我们的关系的故事
about Andrew's land deal and our relationship.
哦 天哪 所有的这些流言 谣传
Oh, my God, all these whispers, these rumors.
谁知道这些都是哪来的?
Who knows where any of that's coming from?
关键是这样的料非常非常多
The point is there's boxes and boxes of this stuff out there.
这个我知道 那是事实  嗯哼
- I know that. That's a fact. - Uh-huh.
就像Will阳痿一样的事实
That's as much a fact as Will's impotence.
我不认为那合适
I don't think that's appropriate.
他不介意 对吧 Will?
He doesn't mind. Do you, Will?
怎样都行 先生
Whatever works, sir.
对吧 瞧? 好队员  没错
- Right, see? Team player. - Yeah.
哦 我手里有一大摞牌呢 女士
Yeah, I got a pretty impressive deck of cards here, ma'am.
没说笑 我喜欢玩牌
No kidding. I love to play cards.
是吗?  没错
- Do you? - Yeah.
你最喜欢的是什么  上海牌
- What's your favorite game? - Shanghai.
我还以为是抽乌龟呢 (老处女)
I would have guessed Old Maid.
想玩钓鱼么? (也是牌类游戏)  当然
want to play go fish? - Sure.
那就来说牌吧  好的
- Why don't you lay 'em out? - All right.
王后 (Q) 我刚提过的盒子
Queen. The boxes I just mentioned.
嗯哼  装满污垢的盒子
Uh-huh. - Boxes full of dirt.
没错  爆炸性的污垢 有害的污垢
Right. - Explosive dirt. Hurty dirt.
是的 你可以开始叫我有害的脏污男
Yeah, you can start calling me the Hurty Dirty Man.
哦 我不会那么叫你
Yeah, I'm not gonna call you that.
好吧
All right.
我不会 你的王是什么?
I'm not. What's your king?
也许是Chung时间
Could be Chung time.
今晚每个人都Dan Chung
Everybody Dan Chung tonight.
Danny喜欢盒子
Danny likes boxes.
然后呢
And then?
哦 我可无法预测未来
Well, I can't predict the future.
Ooh!
Roger Furlong 瞧你一直如此娇羞
Roger Furlong, look at you being all coy.
你是的 哥们
You are, man.
你就是个腼腆的男孩 然后呢?
You're a coy boy. So what?
你和他达成了某种协议? 那就是你想要的?
You'd make some sort of a deal with him? Is that what you're thinking?
他政府班子里的某个高级职位?
For some sort of senior position in his administration?
奇怪的事情发生了  嗯哼
Stranger things have happened. - Uh-huh.
奇怪的事情可以发生
Stranger things could happen.
砰  砰
Boom. - Boom.
你要和我交易吗?
You want to make a deal with me?
在我未来的政府班子里预留个席位?
Have a place in my future administration?
喔 这可是无风起浪啊 对不对 Will?
Wow, that came out of nowhere, didn't it, Will?
就像果阿突如其来的季风 先生 (印度地名)
It's like a sudden monsoon in Goa, sir.
突如其来的季风 他们能提前好几周预测那些东西 你个蠢货
Sudden monsoon. They predict those things weeks in advance, you idiot.
嘿 你看过《沉默的羔羊》吗?
Hey, did you ever see Silence of the Lambs?
哦 当然 那把我吓坏了
Oh, yeah. That scared the living shit out of me.
我知道 很难相信他们有女的联邦探员
I know, it's hard to believe that they have female FBI agents.
哦!  我说笑的
- Oh! - I'm kidding.
我说笑的 我说笑的
I'm kidding. I'm kidding.
我喜欢那种对女性的排斥
I love that kind of misogyny.
我喜欢像那样的女性排斥  是的 那是最好的例子
- I love misogyny like that. - Yeah, it's the best kind.
好吧 不论如何 关键是
Well, anyway, the point is you got
你知道那两个角色 对吧?  没错
- these two characters, right? - Right.
看起来很不一样 但他们能达成共识
That seem to be so different, but they can come to an understanding
并一起工作
and they can actually work together.
你知道吗? 你这点说得很对
You know what? You make such a good point.
你这点说得很对
You make such a good point.
啊哼 澄清一下 Roger
Ahem. Just to be clear, Roger,
你没有索求什么
you're not asking for anything
而我也没有做任何承诺
and I'm not agreeing to anything.
好的
Okay.
显然 我无法明确说出任何事情
Obviously, I can't say anything explicitly.
你也不能 你明白吗
Neither can you. You understand that?
Will 我明白吗?
Will, do I understand?
是的 你明白 先生
Yes, you do, sir.
你听到我们说什么了吗 Will?
Did you hear what we said, Will?
没有 女士
No, ma'am.
好队员  没错
Team player. - Yeah.
我喜欢  没错
I Like it. - Yeah.
好吧 她正在路上 所以我们会把这个放到她的车里
All right, she's on her way, so we'll just put this in her car.
你查了机油吗  没有 谁他妈的会去查机油?
did You check the oil? - No. Who the Fuck checks their oil?
每个人
Everyone.
哦 嘿 Sue来了  哦 谢天谢地
- Oh, hey, Sue's here. - Oh, thank God.
谢谢 Sue  不用谢 Gary
- Thanks, Sue. - You're welcome, Gary.
Hi Shaun  嘿 先生们
- Hi, Shaun. - Hey, gentlemen.
很高兴见到你  Sue 拿一个袋子
- Nice to see you. - Sue, grab a bag.
我们会是恶心家族
We're gonna be the shitty Sopranos.
反正别弄脏我的裙子
Just don't get any mess on my dress.
我的脏东西在你的裙子上 我喜欢这个... 抱歉
My mess on your dress. I like this... sorry.
这之后你得付我车的清洁费
You're paying to have my car cleaned after this.
好吧 首先 别碰 谢谢 我没有...
Okay, first, no touching. Thank you. And I'm not.
好吧 来吧 来搞定这个
Okay, come on. Let's get this over with.
哦 上帝啊 我没法坐进去
Oh, God, there's no way I'm gonna fit in here.
这可比你妈的子宫大 你在那儿呆到了15岁
It's bigger than your mother's womb and you were in there till you were 15.
哦 天哪  好了
- Oh, my God. - There you go.
哦 天哪 我碰到了
Oh, God, I'm touching it.
有东西是湿的 有东西是湿的
Something's wet. Something's wet.
恶 好吧  弄到我的ID卡上了
- Ugh, okay. - It got on my ID badge.
注意你的腿 Lurch (Addams Family 中的大高个)  好吧 伙计们
- Watch your legs, Lurch. - All right, guys.
谁会买双门车啊?  哦 恶心
Who buys a coupe? Oh, gross.
人们会说他不该在那
People will say he shouldn't have been there.
但他已经死了 看在上帝的面上
But he's dead, for God's sake.
我知道
I know.
我知道 我知道 我知道
I know. I know. I know.
我一直在想他最后的时刻
I keep thinking about his last moments.
是的
Yeah.
那个寡妇情况怎么样?
So how is the widow holding up?
她一直哭 就是他妈的一直哭
She's crying a lot. Like a shitload a lot.
她很难过 丈夫被吃 等等
She's upset. Husband eaten, et cetera.
不过她是你的忠实支持者 你该和她谈谈
She's a big fan of yours, though. You should talk to her.
我不知道 那搞不好会看起来很投机
I don't know. It could look opportunistic.
但英雄们没有选择 他们被选择
But heroes don't get to choose, they get chosen.
说到被选择 Dan.com/Egan怎么样了?
Speaking of chosen, how is Dan.com/Egan?
我仍然是个支持者  你也应该是 Danny
- I'm still a fan. - And you should be, Danny.
我就他妈的太了不起了  没错
- I'm fucking awesome. - You are.
但悲伤地说 Selina和Kent Davison对我的命运视而不见
Sadly, though, Selina and Kent Davison are blind to my destiny.
瞧 他们的思维还停留在90年代
See, they're thinking like it's the 1990s.
我的思维已经到了2020年
I'm thinking like it's the 2020s.
你有双眼2.0的视力哈? (双关)
You got 20/20 vision, huh?
Zowie! (Zoe Fleury 歌手)  你喜欢那个?
- Zowie! - You like that?
瞧 我的队伍里需要更多这种人
See, I need more of that on my team.
你现在是这是邀我工作么?
You offering me a job?
我现在手上没有任何空缺职位 但是会有的
I don't have any immediate vacancies, but I will.
六年内 你和我
In six years' time, you and me,
在总统办公室里订披萨还有空袭
Oval Office ordering a pizza and an air strike.
薄脆饼皮 更多弹头
Thin crust, extra warheads.
让滚石在我他妈的客厅里表演
Get the Rolling Stones to perform in my fucking living room.
20/20 哟
20/20, yo.
女士?  Dan 你15分钟的停职已经结束了
- Ma'am? - Dan, your 15 minutes of furlough are over.
我需要你回来 去那混蛋前夫的车里
I need you back. To the Bastardmobile.
好的
Yeah.
你知道 在其他人搞砸它之前
You know, I didn't realize how good I was at this job
我没意识到我在这份工作上做得有多棒
until someone else did it so badly.
差异不是不好  不 不好就是不好
- Different isn't bad. - No, bad is bad.
好吧 那么今天我们要做什么
Okay, so what do we got on the deck for today?
我们有航天局的会议?
We got that NASA meeting?
不 看起来航天局的家伙们得重新安排会议时间
No, it looks like the NASA guys had to reschedule.
哦 去! 我要见航天局的人
Aw, crap. I wanted to meet the NASA guys.
Gary 他们甚至不再在月球上行走了
Gary, they don't even walk on the moon anymore.
他们本质上就是一群在机库里工作的书呆子
They're basically a bunch of nerds who work in a hangar.
那现在是什么?
So what do we got instead?
你有个去Fairfax废品回收场的访问
You have a visit to the waste management plant in Fairfax.
好吧 我都不知道那句话里哪个词比较让我郁闷
Okay, I don't know what is the most depressing word in that sentence.
你能做的就是去见见那群处理垃圾的人
All you got to do is go meet the garbage guys.
你知道的 弄得就像你和普通人一起做脏活
You know, make it look like you're getting your hands dirty with the common man.
然后照些照片给媒体
Get some pictures for the press.
不错的小机会 我安排的
A nice little puff piece. I set it up.
你被停职了 Mike  无薪?
- You're furloughed, Mike. - Without pay?
是的 就是这样 去签Amy桌上的文件
Yeah, that's how it works. Go sign the paperwork on Amy's desk.
试着把你该死的船租出去
Try renting out your fucking boat.
女士 瞧 在这个上面我没有选择
Ma'am, look, I had no choice in this.
Gary才是那个向处理垃圾的人承诺访问的人
Gary's the one who promised the garbage guy a visit.
Gary不会做那种那么愚蠢的事情 对吗 Gary?
Gary wouldn't do something that idiotic, would you, Gary?
哦 在某些场合下 垃圾回收服务...
Well, under certain circumstances, a garbage service...
Ah!
哦 不 不 我知道了
Yeah, no, no. I get it.
我明白了  是的 唷
I understand now. - Yeah. Whew.
嘿 Gary  是的?
- Hey, Gary. - Yeah?
你被停职了  不!
- You're furloughed. - No!
抱歉 我有Sue了
I'm sorry. I got Sue.
不
No.
你得去签Amy桌上的文件
You got to sign the paperwork on Amy's desk.
女士?
Ma'am?
Gary提到过您可以帮我快速搞定护照更新
Gary mentioned you might be able to get my passport renewal fast-tracked.
好吧 Gary 滚出去  去你丫的 Jonah
Okay, Gary, get out. Go fuck yourself, Jonah.
女士 我是G8峰会先遣组
Ma'am, I'm G8 advance team.
去 句号 你丫 句号
Go, period, fuck, period,
感叹号
yourself, exclamation point.
但是 女士 我有帮忙处理垃圾
But, ma'am, I helped with the garbage.
哦 你有帮忙...
Oh, you helped with the...
处理那些垃圾?
with the garbage?
是的 我帮忙处理了那些垃圾
Yeah, I helped with the garbage.
唔 Sue  是?
- Um, Sue. - Yeah?
你能联络一下
Could you get in touch
国务院那他妈的谁吗?
with what's-his-fuck at the State Department?
向您脱帽致敬 我的女士
A doff of the cap to you, my lady.
女士  什么?
- Ma'am. - Yeah?
在我去洗手间的时候你把Gary和Mike停职了?
Did you just furlough Gary and Mike when I was in the bathroom?
没错 所以Sue是新的Gary而你仍然是那个Amy
I did. So Sue's the new Gary and you are still the Amy.
哦  没错
Yeah. - Yeah.
嘿 嘿 我错过了什么?
Hey, hey. What have I missed?
她在无差别地停众人的职
She is furloughing indiscriminately into the crowd.
啊 Amy  借一步说话
Uh, Amy, a quick word.
别告诉我你搞上了那个寡妇
Please don't tell me you got it on with the widow.
告诉我实情 你觉得Selina前途如何?
Tell me honestly. Where do you think Selina's heading?
是什么让你对她有疑虑?
What's making you doubt her?
土地交易的破事 假复合的破事 政府停工的破事
Land deal shit, fake relationship shit, shutdown shit.
你还没说她刚刚和Roger Furlong做了个交易
You left out that she just did a deal with Roger Furlong
而且还对抗抑郁药物有了依赖的事
and is becoming semidependent on antidepressants.
哦 好吧 还能出什么问题啊?
Oh, well, what could possibly go wrong?
好吧 Sue 走吧
Okay, Sue, let's go.
女士 很抱歉
Ma'am, I am so sorry
我没法帮您搞定那寡妇
that I could not get you the widow.
哦 那就是我说的他妈的巨大的失败
Yeah, that was what I would call a massive fuckup.
是的  好吧 报纸们在说
- Yeah. - Well, the newspapers are suggesting
我得为某个蠢货的恐怖死亡而负责
that I am responsible for the grisly death of some idiot.
但是我正在去垃圾站的路上
But I'm on my way to a garbage dump,
所以这是正面的 对吧?
so that's a positive, right?
哦 这个态度不错
Well, that's a good attitude to have.
Amy 为什么除了我之外
Amy, why is everybody else
每个人都在决定我的形象?
in charge of my image except me?
我们得做些什么 Amy  好吧
- We've got to do something, Amy. - Okay.
女士 那个垃圾场在10点15分的时候会有 被污染的淤泥运到
Ma'am, the dump has a contaminated sludge delivery at 10:15,
所以我们的时间有限
so we have a very limited window.
好吧 我只是 我只是想...
Okay, I just... I just want to think...
我们只需要用我们的大脑思考一分钟
we just need to think with our heads for a minute.
或许让我上电视?
Maybe get me on TV?
哦 我们不想要上Janet Ryland的
Well, we don't want to do First Response
第一反应什么之类的  但是...
with Janet Ryland or anything, but I mean...
哦 哦 没错
Oh. Oh, yeah.
没错 是个绝妙的主意
Yeah, that's a great idea.
那就是我想做的 Dan
That's precisely what I want to do, Dan.
好  哦 好吧 那么 是 就是这样
- Good. - Oh, okay, then, yes. Exactly.
你知道吗? 我想得越多
You know what? The more I think about it,
她就越接近我们想做的
she actually might be exactly what we want to do.
她被尊敬 但她并不危险
She's respected, but she's not dangerous.
她保守 她庄重
She's staid, she's stately.
她又老又冷漠
She's old and cold
而我友好又...
and I'm warm and...
年轻?  年轻 没错
- Young? - Young, exactly.
而且我是个母亲
And I'm a mother.
那么我们应该找来Catherine
So we should round up Catherine,
在关键时刻 必要的时候
at gunpoint, if we have to.
也许还有Andrew
And maybe Andrew.
嗯?
Yeah?
诚实地说 全美国都会在看
Honestly, all of America will be watching.
如果那不能实现 这就会是整个旅程的终点
If it doesn't land, then this could be the end to this whole adventure.
别这样 别这样
Come on. Come on.
一惊一乍的女人  滴答 滴答
- Melodrama queen. - Tick tock, tick tock.
淤泥时间  哦 这会是个绝妙的主意
- Sludge time. - Yeah. This is gonna be a great idea.
那么打电话给第一反应  让这件事进行下去
So call First Response, get this thing underway.
我们得终止使Mike和Gary停职
We've got to unenfurlough Mike and Gary.
是终止停职  那就是我刚说的 Amy
- Unfurlough. - That's what I just said, Amy.
好吧? 尽可能找更多的人做这件事
Okay? So let's just throw as many bodies at this as we can.
这就是我们要做的
That's what we're gonna do.
你或许希望戴着这个口罩以防风向改变
You may want to wear this mask in case the wind changes.
哦 真的? 不 我不那么认为
Oh, really? No, I don't think so.
我觉得 唔 哦 好吧
I think... mm, yeah, okay.
不是个坏主意 实际上
That's not a bad idea, actually.
很高兴见到你 Janine
It's great to meet you, Janine.
你的勇气鼓舞了我们所有人
Your bravery has been an inspiration for us all.
女士 我调了三分钟整给您聊小天
Now look, ma'am, I've allotted exactly three minutes
这个时候...  好的 谢谢 Sue
- for small talk, during which... - Okay, thank you, Sue.
在那之后 有最多
Then after that, there's a maximum
10分钟给玻璃...  那足够了 Sue
- of 10 minutes for glass... - That's enough, Sue.
这里有摄影机 摄影机在这
There are cameras. There are cameras here.
如果有任何我能做的...
If there's anything I can do...
能听到有人这么说实在是太好了
It is so nice to hear someone say that.
如果你需要 你就会得到
If you need it, you got it.
愿主保佑你
God bless you.
这片地区的野生动植物
This wildlife in the area,
我在想这个垃圾场会如何影响到它们的生活
I wonder how it's impacted by this very facility.
我们有很多老鼠 如果您指的是那个的话
We get a lot of rats, if that's what you mean.
哦 好吧 那倒是 不是吗? 当然 没错
Oh, well, that makes sense, doesn't it? Of course, yeah.
他曾经在海岸巡逻队服役过 对吗?
And he served in the Coast Guard, is that right?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
如果我能早认识他 那一定是无上的荣幸
It would have been a mighty privilege to have known him.
我确定你知道 Joe
And I'm sure you know, Joe,
在全国范围内
that nationally we spend about $71
每吨垃圾的回收处理费是71美元
per ton of waste on recycling
而收集这些垃圾的费用则是86美元一吨
while we spend $86 per ton on collection.
你有被这个差异困扰过吗?
Do you find this divergence troubling?
女士 我 我只铲垃圾
Ma'am, I-I just shovel it.
我不算这个账  好吧
- I don't account for it. - Okay.
这看起来不怎么样 对吧?
This doesn't look great, does it?
取决于你看的是哪个频道
Depends on which channel you're watching.
我想我们都能从你表现出来的无比的坚强中学习
I think we can all learn from the incredible strength you've shown.
你结婚了吗 Joe?  是的
- Are you married, Joe? - Yes.
啊 那真不错
Ah, that's lovely.